In the past sections, we covered how to wrangle data
在之前的几节课里 我们介绍了如何处理数据
in two different ways, Python and SQL.
包括两种方式 Python 和 SQL
At this point, you might be wondering which one you should use.
你可能会纠结使用哪种方式
The code you write in this higher level APIs,
你在这些高级 API 中编写的代码
first goes through a query optimizer to turn
会先经过查询优化器转换成
it into an actual execution plan before it can be ran.
实际的执行计划 然后才开始跑
Spark's optimizer is called catalysts.
Spark 的优化器被称为 catalyst
Under the hood, catalysts will translate your code to the same DAG.
catalyst 会将代码转换为相同的 DAG
So the good news is that when you run your application,
所以不管你用 SQL 还是 pySpark
you won't notice much difference between using either SQL or by Spark.
都不会有大的区别
The code generated based on the execution plan,
基于执行计划生成的代码
operates on a lower level data abstraction called
在较底层的数据抽象上运行
RDD or Resilient Distributed Data set.
这个底层数据抽象 叫做 RDD 或弹性分布式数据集
When checking the Spark UI, you will often come across
查看 Spark UI 时 你经常会看到
the acronym RDD as well as methods mentioning it.
缩略词 RDD 以及关于它的方法
In Spark's early versions,
在 Spark 的早期版本中
RDDs were the only available data abstraction,
RDD 是唯一可用的数据抽象
and developers had to program using them.
开发人员必须使用它进行编程
In version 1.3, the DataFrame API was introduced.
在 1.3 版中 Spark 引入了 DataFrame API
Then in version 2.0,
然后在 2.0 版中
the DataFrames and data sets APIs were unified.
DataFrames 和 DataFrames API 被合并了
In some cases, we need more flexibility than
在某些情况下 更高级别的 API 并不能满足我们对
what the higher level APIs can provide.
灵活性的需求
So we need to directly interact with RDDs.
所以我们需要直接使用 RDD
You might remember the example I used for explaining
你可能还记得我解释
the difference between imperative and declarative programming.
命令式和声明性编程之间的区别用到的例子
I said that an imperative statement could look like,
我说过 一个命令式语句就好比说
let's get in the car,
先上车
drive two miles down the road to my favorite bakery,
开车两英里到我最喜欢的面包店
go into the shop, search the cake from the counter,
走进商店 从柜台找蛋糕
purchase cake, drive home.
买蛋糕 开车回家
When you deal with RDDs,
当你处理RDD时
you need to use even more detailed through the imperative statements such as,
你要用更详细的命令式语句 例如
let's open the car door, take a seat, start the engine, and so on so forth.
打开车门 坐下 启动发动机等等
Using RDDs gives us a lot of flexibility but the code is harder to write and read.
使用 RDD 为我们提供了极大的灵活性 但代码更难读写
We also lose access to catalysts since this flexibility
并且由于这种灵活性 我们也无法使用 catalyst 了
makes it much more difficult to optimize the code under the hood.
优化代码也变得更加困难
In the next lesson,
下一课中
we will focus on different ways to optimize your Spark code,
我们要看看优化 Spark 代码的不同方法
and will cover how to work with RDDs in more detail.
并将更加详细介绍如何使用 RDD